太陽は雄  男性を表し…
The sun is male, and represents a man...
And the moon is female; representing a woman.
月は雌  女性を表す
太陽と月が交わるということは
When the sun and the moon come together, they become one...
雌雄同体
つまり　完全な存在を表す
...in other words, it represents a perfect being.
When they say "perfect being", are they talking about immortality?
完全な存在って
不老不死のことかな
My guess is that it's something even more incredible.
もっとすごいもんじゃね
もっとすごいもの
Like?
例えば…神様とか
Like... God.
That's right, come!
そうだ　来い
I shall no longer be chained down by You!
もう貴様に縛られ続ける私ではない
I shall drag You down to earth and make You a part of me!
地に引きずり下ろし
我が身の一部にしてくれよう
みんな　無事なのか
Is everyone okay?
What just happened?!
何があった
A job well done, my dear sacrifices.
ご苦労だった　人柱諸君
So you actually did it...!
やりやがったな…
Yes, I've obtained God.
手に入れたよ　神を
'God', you say?!
神だと　そんなことが…
Cut the bullshit-
It's possible.
できるんだよ
If you're in possession of a tremendous amount of energy, that is.
膨大なエネルギーがあればな
エネルギー　はっ　賢者の石
Energy?
A philosopher's stone!
You're joking!
まさか
So you mean, everyone has already been turned into a philosopher's stone?!
じゃあ　もうみんな賢者の石に
Just how many lives were lost...?
一体何人が犠牲に…
この国の人口はおよそ5000万人だ
There are roughly 50 million people in this nation.
野郎
Son of a bitch!
Shit!
くそっ
I've sealed off alchemy.
術は封じたよ
Farewell, my friends.
さらばだ　諸君
お前　それ…
That's...!
Now that I've devoured God,
神を手に入れた私は
今や　手のひらで
it's not impossible for me to create a sun in the palm of my hand.
太陽をつくることさえ可能なのだ
解き放ってみようか ここで
Should I let this loose right here and now?
お前が神とやらを手に入れたときから
The turnabout had already begun from the moment you were in possession of Him.
すでに逆転劇は始まっているんだよ
長い年月を掛け
For this day and for this day only,
計算に計算を重ね
I had positioned my friends,
my philosopher's stones, all across the nation...
この日のために
オレの中の賢者の石を
仲間をこの国全土に配置しておいたのさ
...over a long period of time and with many calculations.
時が来た
The time has come.
He did something he shouldn't have done.
あやつめは
やってはならぬことをしたのだ
We no longer have a body to return to.
我らに戻る体はもはやない
だが　アメストリスの人々には
However, the people of Amestris do.
戻るべき体がある
そうね　彼らの魂を
Yes. Let us return their souls to their respective bodies.
元の体に戻してあげましょう
Hohenheim asked us to, after all.
ホーエンハイムの頼みだし
賢者の石を打ち込んだだけか…
So all you did was to implant your philosopher's stones.
But those are just points.
しょせんは点
円がなければ　術は発動せん
Without a circle, there is no alchemy.
That's a basic principle of alchemy.
錬金術の基本だ
円ならあるさ
But there IS a circle.
オレにもしものことがあっても
A huge, powerful circle that'll activate by itself even if something were to happen to me!
勝手に発動してくれる
とびきりでかくて
パワーのあるやつがなぁ
日食によって
The shadow of the moon that occurs from the solar eclipse!
大地に落ちる月の影さ
先に行くよ　ホーエンハイム
We'll be going on ahead, Hohenheim!
You just continue to get in my way,
don't you, Hohenheim?!
どうあっても邪魔をするか
ホーエンハイム
That's precisely what I came here to do,
そのためにここに来たんだよ
Dwarf in the Flask, Homunculus!
フラスコの中の小人　ホムンクルス
Winry... are you okay?
ウィンリィ　大丈夫かい
What... just happened?
何…今の…
Did we lose consciousness?
オレたち　意識が飛んでたのか
ピナコさんたちも
It happened to you two as well?
そのようだね
Looks like it.
しかし　今のは…
But that was...
なんていうんだろう…こう…
How can I explain it... it was as if...
苦しみの渦の中にいるような感じだった
It felt like I was drowning in a whirlpool of suffering.
Did it work?
やったのか
アメストリスの人々の魂は
The souls of the people of Amestris were returned to their respective bodies.
それぞれの体へ還った
He shouldn't be able to restrain this being he calls 'God' with only the souls of the people of Xerxes.
元から持っていた
クセルクセス人の魂だけでは
ヤツが神と呼ぶものを
押さえ込んでいられないだろう
I can just create another philosopher's stone.
賢者の石はまた作ればいい
A hundred million, or even a billion!
１億でも　１０億でも
Humans, an energy form, are an unlimited source!
人間というエネルギーはいくらでもある
May!
メイ
It's as easy as pie for an Eastern Alchemist to read and utilize the flow of the earth's energy!
地の力の流れを読み
利用するのは錬丹術師のおはこ
The more power he has, the more power we have that we can use as well!
しかも　向こうの力が
大きければ大きいほど
こちらが利用できる力も
大きくなるんです
Sir, look out!
おじ様　正面
Dammit!
くそ
エネルギーの相殺が間に合わん
I don't have enough time to offset the energy!
Please hold out!
ふんばってください　おじ様
防御の陣が壊れる
The defense circle will be destroyed!
It's impossible!
ダメだ
Stand firm, Dad!
父さん　ふんばって
てめぇ　この野郎
You bastard, don't you dare give up!
気ぃ抜くんじゃねぇぞ
Uh-oh.
参ったね　こりゃ
I'm a terrible father, but I want to make you two proud!
ボンクラおやじだけど
いいとこ見せたくなっちまうなぁ
If we don't hurry up, the philosopher's stone inside of Dad will run out!
早くしないと
父さんの中の賢者の石が尽きる
Hurry up, Scar!
まだか　スカー
Ishbalan,
イシュヴァール人よ
錬金術は物質の構築は
I thought that alchemy, the reconstruction of matter,
was a sin against Ishvala, the creator of all!
万物の創造主たる　イシュヴァラへの
冒とくではなかったのか
神を捨てたのか
Have you abandoned your god?!
It seems as though...
貴様らにとって　神とは
...'God' is hardly significant to you all!
しょせん　その程度の存在か　否
Nay!
After you learned the true meaning of despair...
イシュヴァールの内乱で
...during the Ishbalan War...!
絶望を知った貴様は
You must have realized somewhere inside of your heart!
心のどこかで思っていたはず
God does not exist!
神などこの世界のどこにもおらんと
天運も神も信じていなかったが
I believed in neither destiny nor a god,
but one would probably look at this situation and say that the heavens are not on my side.
こういうのを天は我に味方せず
とでもいうのかね…
天は粋な客をよこしたものだ
The heavens brought forth a fitting visitor.
So you're here to avenge your grandfather...
祖父の敵討ちか…
That's fine as well.
それもよかろう
Any last words?
言い残すことはないか
ない
Nay.
悲しい人生だ
A sad life you led.
キング·ブラッドレイ　貴様には
King Bradley, was there no one you loved?
愛する者はいなかったのか
友は　妻は
Friends? Your wife?
妻か…
Wife, eh...
その者に残す言葉は
You have no words to pass on to her?!
何もないというのか
貴様が人造人間だと知ったら…
If she found out that you were a homunculus...!
Brat, quit blabbering on about trifling topics such as love and sadness.
愛だの悲しみだのと
くだらぬ言葉をたれ流すな　小娘
Don't underestimate us.
なめるなよ
She's the woman I chose.
あれは私が選んだ女だ
私とあれの間に遺言などいらん
A will is unnecessary between us.
That's usually how it is between a King and his companion.
王たる者の伴侶とはそういうものだ
くだらぬ問答をしているうちに
Seems like you missed the chance to take revenge as you were caught up in foolish dialogue...
敵を討ち損ねたな　娘よ…
Although my life was lived atop a rail which was already prepared for me...
用意されたレールの上の一生ではあったが
Thanks to you humans...
お前たち人間のお陰で
...I feel like my life was somewhat worthwhile...
まあ　多少…
やり応えのある
よい人生であったよ…
A sign of life?
命の気配
賢者の石だ
It's a philosopher's stone.
This?
これが
大丈夫か
Are you all right?!
あそこまで連れていってくれ
Please take me to that spot...
The transmutation circle is broken!
錬成陣は壊れてるぞ
かまわん
It doesn't matter!
中心なのだ　あそこが
That's the center of it all...!
Got it.
分かった
兄者…
Dear brother, to tell you the truth, I am not completely rid of hatred.
正直　オレの中の憎しみは
消えていない
なのに　その憎しみの相手を
Yet, I'm currently trying to help the ones
whom my hatred is directed at: the Amestrians.
アメストリスを助けようとしている
兄者は正の流れと負の流れと言ったが
You once related it to the flow of positives and negatives,
矛盾したその両方を抱えているオレは…
but where will I, who carry both of those conflicting elements,
be carried off to?!
どこへ流れていくのだろうか
There it is!
きたぞ
ざまぁみやがれ
Serves you right.
That chair you've been sitting high and mighty on is now in pieces.
偉そうに
ふんぞり返ってたイスが粉々だ
You've had your share of fun for your lifetime, bitch.
好き放題やってくれやがったな
この野郎
クソ真理と一緒に
I'll beat the shit out of both you and Truth!
てめぇもぶっとばす
今のは錬丹術なのか
Was that... Eastern Alchemy?
いいや　兄が作り出したものだ
No, it's something my brother invented.
兄は錬金術の研究をしていた
He used to research alchemy.
そこから発展して
And from there, he began to research Eastern Alchemy from Xing.
シンの錬丹術も研究しはじめた
錬丹術は
Eastern Alchemy utilizes the flow of earth's energy.
大地の気の流れを利用する術だ
この国の錬金術は
Alchemy from Amestris utilizes tectonic energy.
地殻エネルギーを利用する
だが　兄は気づいたのだ
But my brother realized...
錬金術師はそれを
...that alchemists are unable to use all of that power.
十分に使いきれていないと
地殻エネルギーと術者の間に
There's something in the way between the alchemist and the tectonic energy.
何か阻害する要素がある
この国に入ったときに感じた
That feeling I got when I first came to this country...
地下を人が
...it felt as though there were people crawling about underground.
はいずり回っているような感覚
そうだ　おそらく
Right.
It's probably the philosopher's stones that were stretched across underground.
国中の地下に張り巡らされた
賢者の石
おじ様は
So Sir, the purpose of your transmutation circle was to return everyone's souls to their bodies?
みんなの魂を元に戻す錬成陣を
Yeah, it worked out.
うまくいった
スカーがやった逆転の錬成陣は
And the purpose of the Turnabout Transmutation Circle Scar activated was to fix this nation's alchemy.
この国の錬金術を正すものだ
スカーの兄は長い研究の結果
After extensive research, Scar's brother began to doubt this nation's alchemy,
この国の錬金術に疑念を抱き
更に国土錬成陣の存在にたどりついた
and additionally, learned of the existence of the Nationwide Transmutation Circle.
そこで  それをベースに
And with that at its base, and utilizing Eastern Alchemy for inscription,
錬丹術で上書きし
賢者の石の力を無効にする
he created the Turnabout Transmutation Circle; one that would nullify the power of a philosopher's stone.
逆転の錬成陣を編み出した
これで
And with this, alchemists are able to use all the tectonic energy to their liking,
賢者の石によって阻害されていた
地殻エネルギーを存分に使える
something that used to be disrupted by philosopher's stones.
このまま　ガンガンいけ
Keep it up!
ヤツに賢者の石を使わせるんだ
Make him use his philosopher's stone!
いつかエネルギー切れを起こす
He'll eventually run out of energy!
いつかって　いつだよ
And when'll that be?!
分からん
I don't know!
分からんがやるしかない
But all we can do is try!
くらえ
Eat this!
懐かしいねぇ
This brings back memories.
前のオレが入った風呂じゃねぇか
I remember bathing in that once.
おやじ殿も入って…
Why don't you take a soak too?
どけ　グリード
Out of the way, Greed!
動くな　そのまま　ゆっくり…
Freeze!
Now, slowly...
ホークアイ中尉か
Lieutenant Hawkeye?
少佐
Major!
な…なんだ
ヤツめ　賢者の石を作りに行ったな
He must have gone up to create more philosopher's stones.
追うよ
We're going after him.
はい
Right!
ついでにあんたを安全な所に
We'll get you somewhere safe too.
すまない
Sorry about this.
肝心なときに役に立たんとは…
Why am I so useless when people need me the most?
兄さん
Brother!
アル　先に行ってろ
You go on ahead, Al!
こいつはオレに用があるらしい
Seems like he wants a piece of me.
アル　行くよ
Let's go, Al.
負けるんじゃないよ  エド
Don't die now, Ed!
はい
Yes'm!
あんた
Dear!
イズミ
Izumi!
って  ゆっくりしてる場合じゃないのよ
We don't have time for this.
大佐をお願い
Take care of the colonel.
Right!
大佐
Colonel!
やっつけなきゃならないヤツが
There's someone that needs a real good spanking, so I'll be off!
上にいるから　行くわね
ケガですか　大佐
Are you injured, Colonel?
目をやられた
They took my vision.
中尉　君の傷の具合はどうだ
What about your wounds, Lieutenant?
また　あなたは…
Seriously...!
ご自分の心配をなさってください
Please worry about yourself!
目が…
Your eyes...!
君はまだ戦えるか
Can you still fight?
はい
Yes!
若
Young master!
グリードだよ
It's Greed.
ったく　お前
Geez, you followed us all the way down-
こんなとこまで　ついて…
ラース
Wrath!
そうか　死んだのか…
So he bit the dust...
満ち足りた顔しやがって
You look so damn satisfied.
腹の立つ
Pisses me off.
グリード
Greed...!
人造人間の矜持を捨てるとは  情けない
Throwing away his pride as a homunculus... how pathetic.
なんで　お前ら
Why are you guys so obedient towards a father like that?
あんな父親に服従してるんだ
つまらないことを聞きますね
What a stupid question.
生みの親に従うのは
Isn't it obvious that we'd obey our own father?
当たり前じゃないですか
つまんねぇのはそっちだ
You're the stupid one here.
当たり前だって
"Obvious" you say?
自分の頭で考えようとしない
You won't even try thinking with your own brain!
思考停止野郎が
分っかんねぇ
I don't get it...
なんで　お前が
Why do you continue to obey him?
あいつの言いなりになってんのか
お前がそんなボロボロになってんのに
He doesn't give a damn even if you're badly hurt like that.
気にも留めないんだぞ
だから　どうしたというのです
So what?!
君たち人間の常識を
Don't apply this "common knowledge" of your human race to us homunculi!
私たち人造人間に
当てはめないでください
この入れ物はもうもちません
This container won't last for very much longer.
ですが　父上と同じく
But since you, like our father,
have Hohenheim's blood in your veins,
ホーエンハイムの血を引くあなたは
我らが兄弟も同然
we're pretty much siblings.
エドワード·エルリック
Edward Elric, give me your body...
私に入れ物を肉体をよこしなさい
...a container!
なっ　何
What?!
いただけません
Unamused.
実にいただけませんね
I'm thoroughly unamused, homunculus Pride.
人造人間　プライド
キンブリー　まさか
Kimblee?! There's no way!
この魂の暴風雨の中で
How could you maintain your own self-awareness in this tempest of souls...?!
自我を保っていられるわけが…
暴風雨
Tempest?
笑わせないでいただきたい
You make me giggle.
怨嗟の声など
Voices of resentment are like a lullaby to me.
私にとっては子守歌に等しい
なぜ邪魔をするのですか
Why are you interfering with me, Kimblee?!
キンブリー
Well, I wouldn't have done anything had you kept on fighting while conserving your pride as a homunculus.
まあ　あなたが
人造人間の矜持を持ったまま
戦っていれば
何もしなかったのですがねぇ
人造人間の誇りだ　矜持だと
However, first, you blab on about your pride as a homunculus,
のたまっておきながら
我が身に危険が訪れた途端
then just as your life is in danger,
下等生物と見下していた
you proceed to escape into the container of a human, a being you looked down on as inferior.
人間の入れ物に逃げ込もうとする
あなた　美しくない
You...
...lack elegance.
殺される
I'm going to be killed!
あなたは
You don't understand Edward Elric!
エドワード·エルリックを分かっていない
セリム
Selim!!
バカな…自身を賢者の石にして
Impossible...!
He turned himself into a philosopher's stone to infiltrate me?!
逆に私に侵入してくるだと
捕らえたぜ　セリム
I've got you now, Selim!
やめろ…
Stop...
やめろ
Stop...!
やめてくれぇ
Please, stop!!
お前の本体か
So this is your true self.
全部終わったら
I'd better go and apologize to Madam Bradley after all this is over.
ブラッドレイ夫人に謝りに行かなきゃな
そこで待ってろよ　バカセリム
Just wait there, stupid brat.
ママ…ママ…
Mommy... Mommy...
Ever since that day passed,
あの日からずっと
Ano hi kara zutto
I promised myself that I'd never cry.
泣かないと決めてきたけど
Nakanaito kimetekitakedo
But even while I hoarded up the pain,
痛みを重ねても
Itami wo kasanetemo
there was something I couldn't forgive myself for.
何かを許せずにいた
Nanika wo yurusezu ni ita
I'll never be able
もう戻れない
Mou modorenai
to return to those days.
いくつもの日々
Ikutsumo no hibi
I'm still powerless.
僕はまだ何もできずに
Boku wa mada nanimo dekizuni
I watch as the shards of memories disappear, one by one;
君のいた記憶の破片
Kimi no ita kioku no kakera
memories of when you were still with me.
またひとつ 消えてゆく
Mata hitotsu kieteyuku
I long to become
今日よりもっと
Kyou yori motto
stronger than I am now,
強くなりたい
Tsuyoku naritai
so that my voice will eventually reach you.
この声がいつか届くように
Kono koe ga itsuka todokuyouni
If the wind happens to stop
歩き続けて
Arukitsuzukete
in the midst of my long journey,
風が止んだら
Kaze ga yandara
I'll look up at the sky in search of you.
君を探して空見上げるよ
Kimi wo sagashite sora miageruyo
Beyond the daybreak, a ray of light breaks free.
夜明けの先に光がさすよ
Yoake no saki ni hikari ga sasuyo
A rainbow spans across the sky.
虹がかかるよ
Niji ga kakaruyo
次回　鋼の錬金術師
日本語字幕仕上げ：XIAOBIN
The strong arms roars; the flame thunders forth.
Fullmetal　Alchemist
第６２話　『凄絶なる反撃』
Staking their existence, the people give their full measure!
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
何かを得るためには
Yes! The final battle is now here!
同等の代価が必要
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Episode 62, A Fierce Counterattack.
If one wishes to gain something,
one must present something of equal value.